{
    "id": "6193efa41a5d4019b37fc29f1c3c80b7",
    "title": "Simple Present Or Present Continuous",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Father …………………….. the newspaper every day after breakfast.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habitual actions.",
            "answers": [
                "reads",
                "read",
                "is reading"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ……………………….. to church twice a week.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habitual actions and routines.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "are going",
                "goes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The child …………………………… with her dog.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about an action or situation going on at the moment of speaking.",
            "answers": [
                "plays",
                "is playing",
                "play"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. spending time with her dogs.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about likes, dislikes, habits, routines etc.",
            "answers": [
                "enjoy",
                "is enjoying",
                "enjoys"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister ………………………….. research in molecular biology.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "is doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What …………………………. tomorrow?",
            "description": "The present continuous is often used to talk about pre-planned future events.",
            "answers": [
                "do you do",
                "are you doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Light ………………………… faster than sound.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "travel",
                "travels",
                "is traveling"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ……………………….. out, we will be in trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "finds",
                "is finding"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My uncle …………………………… tomorrow.",
            "description": "The present continuous is often used to talk about future events, if the plan already exists. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "is arriving"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………. at a bank.",
            "description": "The simple present is used for more permanent situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "works",
                "is working"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………. a short term course in computer science at the moment.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used for temporary situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "is doing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….  a lot.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is reading",
                "reads"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}